Finding Aid for the Franklin Vesperian Society Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Franklin Vesperian Society Papers
undated
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0156
.42 linear feet
Organization Note:
The Franklin Vesperian Society was a literary society created by the students of the University of Nashville in the early to middle 19th century. This all male group of writers would meet to discuss an interesting broad range of topics and write essays give speeches about them. The collection covers a series of essays starting from 1828 to 1831 which were created by some of its members. Topics range from contemporary issues to religion and nature.
Scope and Content Note:
This collection is a half Hollinger box which is .2085 linear feet that contain the writings of members of the society.
- Folders--Writings (Box 1)
  - Alexander, R- “The Unequal Distribution Among the Human Family”, November 1830 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alexander, R- “Essay on Phrenology”, July 1831 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Andrews, R.L- “The Origins and Use of Honey”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hay, J.G- “The Equality of Human Happiness”, November 1830 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Hay, P- “The Progress of Literature and Society from the Century to the Present”, October 1828 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hay, P- “The Influence of Custom”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Hoge, T- “A Brief View of the Natural Evidence of the Immortality of the Soul”, October 1830 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hoge, T- “Legends of the West”, February 1831 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - McPhail, D- “Essay on Water”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sconce, T.M- “Essay on Intemperance”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Weldon, R (Reader)- “Essay on Historical Reading”, October 1831 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified- “Essay on Agriculture”, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)